{
  "id": "apes_ch12",
  "displayName": "Chapter 12",
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Which statement is false?",
      "choices": [
        "There is enough food currently being grown to feed all of the world\u0027s people.",
        "Not getting enough to eat is often due to poverty.",
        "About one in six world citizens does not get enough food to eat.",
        "Political upheaval, corruption, and war rarely affect food being distributed to those who need it."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "Chronic malnutrition means",
      "choices": [
        "not getting enough calories in your diet.",
        "poor.",
        "a diet lacking enough protein and key nutrients.",
        "a diet lacking iron and carbohydrates."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "A long-term diet lacking trace amounts of iodine may result in",
      "choices": [
        "goiter.",
        "fatigue and mental retardation.",
        "vitamin A deficiency.",
        "anemia."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "A severe shortage of food accompanied by long-term hunger of most of the population, many deaths, and social disruption is called",
      "choices": [
        "mass starvation.",
        "chronic malnutrition.",
        "famine.",
        "warfare."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Ironically, those who are overnourished face similar health problems of those who are undernourished.",
      "choices": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "These foods provide almost 50% of daily calories consumed by people of the world.",
      "choices": [
        "fish and rice",
        "wheat, rice, and corn",
        "potatoes and beef",
        "potatoes, rice, and cabbage"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "Industrialized agriculture is also called high-input agriculture because",
      "choices": [
        "many resources must be used to gain a high crop yield.",
        "high-outputs of crops result.",
        "this type of farming requires large amounts of sunlight, time, animal work, animal wastes for fertilizers, etc.- that is, many natural materials.",
        "it takes much human work to gain high crop yields."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "Which type of farming is most used by the poor tropical farmer?",
      "choices": [
        "greenhouse agriculture",
        "high-input agriculture",
        "slash-and-burn agriculture",
        "plantation agriculture"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Soil \"layers\" of distinctive composition are called soil",
      "choices": [
        "horizons.",
        "levels.",
        "zones.",
        "thicknesses."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "The green revolution was made possible by large inputs of water, fertilizers, and pesticides, increasing the number of crops grown per year per plot of land, and",
      "choices": [
        "developing high-yield crops.",
        "developing richer soils.",
        "increasing the amount of land used for farming.",
        "using aquaculture."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "For thousands of years we have been modifying plants by crossbreeding and hybridization. These processes have yielded the domesticated crop plants we eat today. Aside from the 10-15 years it takes to develop a new variety of tomato or corn, what disadvantage is there to new varieties produced by this method?",
      "choices": [
        "all of the choices",
        "Pests and diseases reduce the plants\u0027 yield/resistance/vigor within 5-10 years.",
        "The cost is prohibitively expensive.",
        "People soon get tired of the taste."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Meat animals (primarily cattle, pigs, and chickens)",
      "choices": [
        "are mostly in feed lots, with feed grains supplied by the farmer.",
        "mostly live in large buildings, fed grains, living out their lives indoors.",
        "are mostly grazed under open sky, eating plants available to them.",
        "are either grazed in open fields and rangelands (about 50%) or live in confined pens/cages/buildings (about %)."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "The fastest growing area of food production currently is",
      "choices": [
        "fisheries.",
        "aquaculture.",
        "grain production.",
        "livestock production."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "The \"blue revolution\" refers to",
      "choices": [
        "cleaning the air of pollutants.",
        "cleaning the oceans of pollutants.",
        "aquaculture.",
        "changing the world diet from meat to fish."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Topsoil erosion leads to",
      "choices": [
        "pollution of aquatic systems.",
        "loss of soil nutrients.",
        "all of the choices",
        "desertification."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Repeated annual application of irrigated water in dry climates leads to a buildup of salts in upper soil layers in a process called",
      "choices": [
        "desertification.",
        "water erosion.",
        "waterlogging.",
        "salinization."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Genetically modified (GM) foods",
      "choices": [
        "have been acclaimed universally as a remarkable and needed agricultural breakthrough.",
        "potentially have many advantages.",
        "are engineered so that there are no environmental problems.",
        "all of the choices"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "The kind of chemical used to kill pest plants is called a/an",
      "choices": [
        "insecticide.",
        "herbicide.",
        "rodenticide",
        "fungicide."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "An old method of farming has been found to be helpful in keeping pest populations low. This practice is",
      "choices": [
        "applying animal manure to crop fields.",
        "keeping seed from one season to be planted the next season.",
        "crop rotation.",
        "deep lowing of the soil."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "In order to help improve food production, governments sometimes ________ as a way of helping farmers.",
      "choices": [
        "keep food prices artificially low",
        "provide subsidies, including tax breaks, to keep farmers in business",
        "import food from other countries",
        "take a \"hands off\" approach, letting the marketplace decide prices"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "Terracing, contour planting, strip planting, and wind breaks all have this in common: they are mainly used to",
      "choices": [
        "prevent soil erosion.",
        "increase crop production.",
        "allow small farmers to stay in business.",
        "maximize soil water retention."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "In terms of being healthy and living longer, studies indicate the poorest diet",
      "choices": [
        "is high in vegetables and fruits, and low in meats.",
        "includes moderate amounts of meat, cheese, and seafood.",
        "has a very high meat and starch component.",
        "is vegetarian."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    }
  ]
}